DOUG CAMPBELL

Email: dcampbellcreative@gmail.com | Phone: 843-680-1296

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/douglass-campbell/ | Portfolio: https://www.dougcampbell.io/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Full Stack Software Developer with extensive experience in graphic design and business management. Specializes in creating frontend interfaces using React, JavaScript, and other tools. Quick learner who thrives on finding creative ways to solve problems.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

React

JavaScript

TypeScript

Java

HTML

CSS

Tailwind

Mantine UI

Source Control

SQL

WebFlow

NodeJS

Adobe Illustrator

Figma

Microsoft Office

EDUCATION

MIDLANDS TECHNICAL COLLEGE

Columbia, SC September 2023 - May 2024

Jr Full Stack Engineer Certificate

28-week Training Program: Development Basics & Front End, Intermediate Programming, Databases, Web Servers, Front End Frameworks (REACT), Scrum/Agile, and Final Project

Soft Skill Training: Verbal Communication, Time Management & Organization, Enhancing Your Professionalism, December 2023

UNIVERSITY OF SOUTH CAROLINA

Columbia, SC

Bachelor of Arts, Visual Communications

Understanding Personality Types, Job Search and Interviewing

August 2008 – December 2012

EXPERIENCE

2NDSUN - Ecommerce start up

UI Developer

Denver, CO

September 2022 – Present

Develop user interfaces with REACT.

- Implemented Mantine UI component library (100+ React components) to create complex UI elements by reading the documentation, writing code, and integrating library into existing codebase.
- Creatively solved a variety of UI issues by translating Figma designs into fully responsive pages and React components using Mantine's Styles API and CSS-in-JS syntax.
- Implemented React Query library to make CRUD operations with backend server to create users and fetch and mutate data.

SHOPL – universal shopping plug in start up

Atlanta, GA

Frontend Software Engineering Intern

Created web pages and collected data for plugin.

August 2022 – November 2022

- Participated in stand ups three times weekly to discuss progress and plan future work.
- Collected data, created regular expressions, and wrote JavaScript web-scraping snippets, integrating 100 shopping sites into extension.

HWY 55 BURGERS, SHAKES, AND FRIES – regional burger franchise

Lugoff and Elgin, SC

Owner Operator

December 2015 – February 2022

Supervised 40+ employees, and oversaw hiring, training, financial and quality management for two franchises.

- Managed operations and success of franchises to achieve top 5% volume in SC regularly.
- Adapted business model to prosper during pandemic and grow sales 10% without indoor dining.
- Increased customer engagement and sales by developing marketing materials for billboards, social media, and print.

DEW LEARNING - eLearning curriculum organization

Charleston, SC

Graphic Designer

October 2013 - June 2014

Designed and created graphics for online homeschool curriculum.

- Created 50+ interactive lessons as part of an online home school curriculum using Adobe Creative Suite and a proprietary content management system, ensuring consistent design across multiple lessons and various subjects.
- Collaborated with colleagues, project managers and 10+ teachers daily to create an immersive learning experience for students.